Mohammed Hamd

Detail-Oriented with Six Years of Customer Service Experience

North York, ON M3C 1L3 m.sulieman64@gmail.com 647-785-8083

Highly motivated and detail-oriented with 6 years of customer service experience. Friendly and helpful individual who has the ability to learn new procedures quickly and efficiently.

Work Experience

Outbound Sales Representative

Bell Canada/ Nordia - Toronto, ON October 2017 to July 2021

- Demonstrating mastery of outbound representative call script.
- Properly prob customers and selling residential products and services based upon customer needs.
- Developing effective relationships with call center departments through effective communication.
- Effectively exceeded sales goals by presenting company products and services to current and potential clients.
- Demonstrating ability to interact and maintain effective working team relationships with company employees, and management.
- Engaging existing customers in order to upsell individual accounts.
- Effectively run a sales presentation by actively listening, overcoming objections, and building consensus with prospective clients.

Technical Support Representative

Virgin Mobile /Nordia - Toronto, ON March 2020 to May 2020

- Assisted customers with technical issues.
- Resolved customer's complaints and concerns with strong verbal and negotiation skills.
- Maintained composure and patience in the face of difficult customers
- Extensive knowledge of computers software and hardware, and techniques to troubleshoot
- Strong professional communication skills with other technical support specialists and clients
- Escalated support desk tickets to a higher level in the most crucial circumstances and after considerable time had been spent on a single ticket.

Security Guard

Reilly Security Services - Toronto, ON April 2016 to August 2017

- Performed patrol duties within assigned areas to guard against theft, shoplifting, vandalism and fire.
- Handled emergency situations effectively; medical emergencies, accidents and other threats.
- Wrote reports of daily activities and irregularities, such as equipment or property damage, theft, presence of unauthorized persons, or unusual occurrences.
- Called police or fire departments in cases of emergency, such as fire or presence of unauthorized persons.

- Circulated among visitors, patrons, and employees to preserve order and protect property.
- Responded to requests for assistance at the building.
- Checked passes and credentials of persons seeking to enter the building.

Merchandise Flow Team-Member

Target - Toronto, ON

November 2014 to March 2015

- Kept merchandise organized and accessible for customers as per store guidelines.
- Helped drive sales by pulling merchandise quickly and accurately from the warehouse.
- Moved merchandise using bar-code scanner technology (P.D.I).
- Organized and maintained warehouse.
- Created a pleasant and safe shopping environment.
- Dealt with customers to ensure customer satisfaction.

Volunteer

Eritrean Community Centre of Toronto - Toronto, ON April 2014 to October 2014

- Called members and invite to upcoming community centre events.
- Assisted with workshops and research development.
- Provided community resources and referrals to members.
- Interpreted for newcomers from Arabic to English.
- Assisted with the organization and facilitation of various events, including the setup and take-down of various event-related booths and other materials.

Customer Service Representative

S.T.C Saudi Telecommunication Company January 2013 to June 2013

- Demonstrated a high standard of customer service.
- Provided and process information in response to inquiries, concerns and requests about products and services.
- Monitored incoming and outgoing telephone calls, emails and faxes.
- Responded promptly to customer inquiries and set up new customer accounts.
- Managed critical calls dealing with problematic situations with complaining clients.
- Provided pricing and billing information and ensure customer satisfaction.
- Trained how to identify critical situations and calls, and how to manage them according to the company's protocol.
- Handled online updates for methods of payment, addresses and other personal information for clients.

Cyber Assistant

M.S Cyber

December 2005 to March 2008

- Worked as a customer service representative and installed OS, Software and assembled of new computers.
- Interacted one-on-one with clients, assessed their needs in order to provide them with accurate information.
- Assisted customers with issues or questions regarding using computer software.
- Provided services such as encoding, printing and faxing to the customer.
- Dealt with problematic situations with challenging clients and ensuring satisfaction.

• Ensured the security and the smooth running of OS and software operations.

Education

Course in Effective Persuasion and Public Speaking

Ryerson University - Toronto, ON April 2015 to July 2015

Course in Advanced Customer Focused Application

Ryerson University - Toronto, ON March 2015 to June 2015

Course in Microsoft Certified IT Professional M.C.I.T.P

Soft Tools Institute - Pune July 2012 to December 2012

Course in Cisco Certified Network Association

Soft Tools Institute - Pune July 2012 to December 2012

BCOM in Marketing

PUNE University - Pune April 2008 to May 2012

Skills

- Technical Support (3 years)
- Customer Service (4 years)

Languages

- English Advanced
- Arabic Advanced

Certifications and Licenses

Ontario Security Guard License

April 2016 to November 2017

Emergency First Aid and CPR

January 2016 to Present

Additional Information

• Languages: Multilingual - English, Arabic and Tigrinya